A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Natural and Historic Resources, 2017-2021 (bulk 2018-2021)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Secretary of Natural and Historic Resources, 2017-2021 (bulk 2018-2021)
The Library of Virginia
53527
6.55 cubic feet (15 Boxes)
Virginia Secretary of Natural and Historic Resources
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Virginia Secretary of Natural Resources circa January 12, 2022.
Historical Information
In 1970, the Governor's Management Commission Study recommended the creation of six "Deputy Governors" to assist the Chief Executive in his managerial duties. Compatible functions of government were grouped under these administrative heads, who would serve as the Governors top management team or "secretariats," as they are called now.
In 1970, the Governor's Management Commission Study recommended the creation of six "Deputy Governors" to assist the Chief Executive in his managerial duties. Compatible functions of government were grouped under these administrative heads, who would serve as the Governor's top management team. The Office of Secretary of Commerce and Resources was created on April 8, 1972. The Secretary of Commerce and Resources was responsible for assisting the Governor in implementing policies for the conservation and use of natural resources, for promoting economic development, providing managerial guidance and direction to Commerce and Resources agencies, and developing and promoting Commerce and Resources programs and budgets. In 1984 the Secretariat was split into two separate offices, the Secretary of Economic Development and the Secretary of Natural Resources. The Secretary of Natural Resources was responsible for the direction of, or had jurisdiction over, the following state agencies and boards: Department of Conservation and Recreation, Department of Environmental Quality, Department of Game and Inland Fisheries, Department of Historic Resources, Marine Resources Commission, Museum of Natural History, and the Virginia Council on Indians. The Secretary of Natural Resources also served as the chairman of the Virginia Land Conservation Foundation, and was a Board Member of the Chesapeake Bay Commission. Additionally, the Secretary of Natural Resources was responsible for many smaller boards and commissions related to water control, pollution, rivers, waste management, and other environmental and recreational issues.
Biographical Information
Matthew Strickler served as the Secretary of Natural Resources from January 2018-September 27, 2021. He was the Chief Resilience Officer for the Commonwealth of Virginia. Before joining the Northam Administration, he served as Senior Policy Advisor to Democratic members of the House of Representatives Committee on Natural Resources. Immediately prior to his time on Capitol Hill, Matt worked in the Virginia General Assembly as a legislative assistant to then-state Senator Ralph Northam. Originally from Lexington, Virginia, Matt holds master's degrees in public policy and marine science from the College of William and Mary and the Virginia Institute of Marine Science.
Ann Jennings served as the Secretary of Natural and Historic Resources from September 2021-January 2022. Previously, Ann was the Deputy Secretary of Natural Resources for the Chesapeake Bay under Secretary of Natural Resources Matt Strickler in the office of Governor Ralph Northam. Prior to that position, she was the Virginia Director of the Chesapeake Bay Commission, a tri-state legislative commission created to advise the General Assemblies of Maryland, Pennsylvania, and Virginia on matters of Bay-wide concern. Prior to the Commission, Ann served as the Virginia Executive Director of the Chesapeake Bay Foundation. Ann's career also includes work as a biologist with the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service. Originally from Virginia Beach, Ann received a bachelor's degree in biology from Virginia Tech and a master's degree in wildlife and fisheries sciences from Texas A and M University. Ann is a graduate of the Virginia Natural Resources Leadership Institute and the Sorensen Institute's Political Leaders Program.
Katie Sallee was the Confidential Assistant to the Secretary of Natural Resources from March 2019/June 2021 to January 14, 2022. Prior to her appointment, Katie was a Field Organizer for the League of Conservation Voters and previously served as a legislative intern in the office of Delegate Betsy Carr.
Meryem Karad was the Confidential Assistant to the Secretary of Natural Resources from November 2020-November 2021. Meryem previously served under Governor Terry McAuliffe in this role.
Scope and Content
The Secretary of Natural and Historic Resources records, 2017-2021, contain correspondence, documents, reports, and other materials pertaining to the work conducted during Virginia Governor Ralph Northam's administration. The materials were created or collected 2017-2021, (bulk 2018-2021) although some documents may pre-date this time period. Major topics include the following: sea level rise in coastal Virginia, flood risk, land conservation programs, Chesapeake Bay programs, Fort Monroe, the Watershed Implementation Program, and the Atlantic Coast Pipeline and the Mountain Valley Pipeline.
The records consist of 15 archival boxes and are divided into five series, reflecting how the materials were received upon transfer. Series I. Records of Matt Strickler; Series II. Records of Ann Jennings; Series III. Records of Ann Jennings and Katie Sallee; Series IV. Records of Meryem Karad; Series V. Constituent Correspondence.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Records of Matt Strickler
Series II. Records of Ann Jennings
Series III. Records of Ann Jennings and Kate Sallee
Series IV. Records of Meryem Karad
Series V. Constituent Correspondence.
Contents List
- Series I. Records of Matt Strickler, 2017-2021 (bulk 2017-2019)., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 1-3)
  The records of Matthew Strickler consist primarily of reports and documentation from local, state and federal government officials, and various associations. Subject files include agreements, legislation, memorandums, presentations, and reports. Topics include the Virginia Coastal Resilience Master Plan, sea level rise, flood risk, ash ponds, the James River Water Authority project, Fort Monroe's Jefferson Davis Arch removal, the Atlantic Coast Pipeline and the Mountain Valley Pipeline, the Hampton Roads Bridge Tunnel, Thimble Shoal Tunnel, and VDOT's bird hazing plan, among others.
  - USGS thumb drive (contents currently unknown), undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Regional Greenhouse Gas Initiative, 2018 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Acts of Assembly, Chapter 504: An Act to establish the Carbon Sequestration task force, 2021 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Natural Gas Header Improvement Project, 2019 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mountain Valley Pipeline, 2018 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Atlantic Coast Pipeline and Wintergreen Resort, 2018 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Solar sites and the impact on pollinators, birds, and native vegetation, 2019 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Meeting with national climate and energy funders, 2018 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sea level rise, flood risk, and the Virginia Coastal Resilience Master Plan, 2018-2019 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sea level rise, flood risk, and the Virginia Coastal Resilience Master Plan, 2018-2019 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Sea level rise, flood risk, and the Virginia Coastal Resilience Master Plan, 2018-2019 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sea level rise, flood risk, and the Virginia Coastal Resilience Master Plan, 2018-2019 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sea level rise, flood risk, and the Virginia Coastal Resilience Master Plan, 2018-2019 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - National Oceanic and Atmospheric Association (NOAA) Chesapeake Bay Office, circa 2018 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Virginia's land conservation programs, 2018-2021 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Virginia's land conservation programs, 2018-2021 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Virginia's land conservation programs, 2018-2021 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Land Conservation Foundation, 2018-2019 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Brandy Station and Cedar Mountain Battlefields State Park feasibility study, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Chesapeake Conservation Partnership, 2019 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Overview of the Chesapeake Bay Preservation Act, Office of the Secretary of Natural Resources (OSNR) Bay Act Working Group, 2019 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Chesapeake Bay Program (CBP), Principal's Staff Committee, 2019 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Nature Conservancy, 2018 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Environmental Justice, 2019 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - World River Center bid and the International White Water Hall of Fame, 2018-2019 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Department of Defense (DOD) installations and ranges, circa 2018 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Lake Merriweather, Goshen Dam, 2019 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Lewis and Clark Trail Heritage Foundation, Inc. Annual Report, 2017-2018 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Trails Alliance, 2019 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Emancipation Trail, 2019 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fort Monroe, circa 2019 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Fort Monroe, Jefferson Davis Memorial Arch removal, 2019 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Fort Monroe, Jefferson Davis Memorial Arch removal, 2019 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Watershed Implementation Plan (WIP) Phase III, 2016-2019 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Oyster and submerged aquatic vegetation (SAV) restoration and guidance, 2019 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Agriculture and forestry groups and council, 2018 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - North Landing River/Albemarle Sound Estuarine Symposium, 2018 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Striped bass assessment and conservation, 2019 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Parallel Thimble Shoal tunnel, 2018 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Hampton Roads Bridge Tunnel (HRBT), Virginia Department of Transportation (VDOT), and the Bird Hazing Plan, 2020 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Coal Combustion Residuals, Ash Pond Closure Assessment, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Coal Combustion Residuals, Ash Pond Closure Assessment, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Coal Combustion Residuals, Ash Pond Closure Assessment, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Coal Combustion Residuals, Ash Pond Closure Assessment, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Possum Point Power Station and removal of surface water from Ash Pond E, 2018 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - James River Water Authority (JRWA) Project, 2019 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - James River Water Authority (JRWA) Project, 2019 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - James River Water Authority (JRWA) Project, 2019 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Disaster and Emergency Management Laws, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Effectiveness of Virginia's Water Resource Planning and Management, Joint Legislative Audit and Review (JLARC), circa 2018-2021 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dams in process of decommissioning, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Opportunity for welfare reform in Central Appalachia, Appalachian Sky, circa 2018 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Department of Conservation and Recreation (DCR), Decision Brief, Utilization of Bond Funding, circa 2016 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources, (SNR) Boards, circa 2018-2019 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 2019-2020 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 2018-2020, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Meetings: various agendas and memos, 2018 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Fleet vehicle management correspondence, 2019 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Draft executive order: Establishment of the Virginia Stem Commission, circa 2019 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Governor's Cabinet Exercise Agenda, 2019 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Natural Resources Law Enforcement (NRLE) Diversity Hiring and Recruitment, 2019 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 2018 Session, House Bill No. 1186…relating to ground water withdrawal permits; priority for human consumptive use; public suppliers, 2018 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Governor's Working Papers: Entry into the Agency, circa 2019 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Series II. Records of Ann Jennings, 2010-2021, Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 4-6)
  The records of Ann Jennings contain correspondence, reports, plans, and notes. The topics cover the Watershed Implementation Program Phase III, Chesapeake Bay Stakeholders Advisory Group, Wastewater Infrastructure Policy Working Group, and the Chesapeake Bay Program, among others.
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP), Chesapeake Bay Total Maximum Daily Load (TMDL) report and appendices (AV material), 2010 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP) Phase III, Draft of Executive Review, 2018 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP) Phase III, agricultural sector and planning district commissions (PDC's), 2018 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP) Phase III, Chesapeake Bay Total Maximum Daily Load (TMDL), 2019 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP) Phase III, Chesapeake Bay Total Maximum Daily Load (TMDL), 2019 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP) Phase III, 2018-2019 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP) Phase III, 2018-2019 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP) Phase III, 2018-2019 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP) Phase III, 2018-2019 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP) Phase III, sector outreach, 2019 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP) Phase III, WIP final timeline and comments, 2019 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP) Phase III, development, 2019 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP) Phase III, litigation, 2019 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP) Phase III, Voluntary Agriculture Best Management Practices task force, 2019-2021 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Watershed Implementation Program (WIP) Phase III, state lands, 2020-2021 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Local Government Advisory Committee (LGAC) roundtables, 2018 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Chesapeake Bay Stakeholders Advisory Group, 2018 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Chesapeake Bay Stakeholders Advisory Group, 2018 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Chesapeake Bay Implementation Team, 2020-2021 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources (SNR) call with planning district commissions (PDC's) regarding Chesapeake Bay restoration, 2020 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Programmatic and numeric milestones, 2020-2021 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Executive Order Number XX (2019) Virginia leading by example to restore the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries, 2019 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Wastewater Infrastructure Policy Working Group (WWIWG), 2018-2021 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Wastewater Infrastructure Policy Working Group (WWIWG), 2018-2021 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - HB1422/SB704 Chesapeake Bay Watershed Implementation Plan (WIP) initiatives, nutrient management plans, 2020 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Chesapeake Bay Preservation Act Work Group, 2019 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Chesapeake Bay Program (CBP) budget, CBIG, and CBRAP, 2019 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Chesapeake Bay Program (CBP) Management Board, 2019-2020 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Chesapeake Bay Program (CBP) Management Board, 2019-2020 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Climate Change Action Team, 2021 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Chesapeake Bay Program (CBP) Partnership, Principal's Staff Committee, 2020-2021 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Chesapeake Bay Program (CBP) Partnership, Principal's Staff Committee, 2020-2021 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Conowingo Watershed Implementation Plan, 2020-2021 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Think-soil.com (Electronic material), circa 2018-2021 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Series III. Records of Ann Jennings and Katie Sallee, 2017-2021, Extent: 1.5 boxes. (Box 7-8)
  The records of Ann Jennings and Katie Sallee cover a wide range of topics including the following: aquaculture, Chesapeake Bay Bridge Tunnel, Watershed Implementation Plan Phase III, Maryland Coastal Bays Program, General Assembly, oyster restoration, and the Coastal Resilience Master Plan. The types of materials represented are regulations, correspondence, mitigation, budgets, and reports, among others.
  - Halifax NOI, TLP Request, and PAD, prepared by Kleinschmidt, (electronic material: CD), 2021 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Albemarle-Pamlico National Estuary Partnership (APNEP), 2017-2018 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Aquaculture, 2018 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Chesapeake Bay Bridge Tunnel (CBBT), 2018 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Chesapeake Bay Comprehensive Plan (CBCP), Army Corps/NFWF, 2018 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Mitigation documents: Volkswagen, Mountain Valley Pipeline, DEQ Carbon, U.S. Climate Alliance, and others, 2018 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Regulation: Laurel Fork, Exceptional State Waters (ESW), 2018 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Regulations: Nutrient credits pertaining to water quality, 2018 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Mountain Valley Pipeline (MVP) mitigation discussion with Virginia Environmental Endowment (VEE), 2018 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Regulation: Mercury switches, 2018 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Maryland Coastal Bays Program, Policy Committee Briefing Book, 2018 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Maryland Coastal Bays Program, Policy Committee Briefing Book, 2018 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Maryland Coastal Bays Program, Policy Committee Briefing Book, 2018 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - College Lake Dam funding request, City of Lynchburg, 2018 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Budget, 2018-2019 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Dyke Marsh Restoration, Alexandria, Virginia, 2018-2019 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Dupont Waynesboro Trustee Council, Resolution for Mount Joy Acquisition, 2018-2020 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Patrick Henry Building recycling plan, 2018 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Appomattox River Trail Master Plan, circa 2018-2021 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Dominion Atlantic Coast Pipeline (ACP) mitigation, 2018-2021 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Chesapeake Bay Environmental Literacy Summit, 2019 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Chesapeake Bay Environmental Literacy Leadership Summit, Ensuring Equity in Environmental Education, grant, 2019 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Chlorophyll assessment in water bodies, 2019 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Dupont Settlement, Shenandoah River Access development, 2019 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) and Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) reviews, 2019 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - General Assembly, 2019 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - National Fish and Wildlife (NFWF) and Virginia Environmental Endowment (VEE), 2019 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - U.S. Army Corps of Engineers (USACE), subaqueous bottomlands, 2019 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Governor Decision Request: Draft Phase III Watershed Implementation Plan (WIP), 2019 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Governor Decision Request: Draft Phase III Watershed Implementation Plan (WIP), 2019 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - HB1673 Comment and SB1048 Comment, 2018-2020 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Regulation: Ammonia, 2019 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - ACCC stream fencing, 2020 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Department of Corrections (DOC) State Farm, 2020 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - General Assembly, 2020 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Oyster restoration, 2020 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - General Assembly, 2021 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Council on Environmental Justice Meeting, 2021 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Coastal Resilience Master Plan, 2021 October (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Coastal Resilience Master Plan, 2021 November (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Budget Proposal, 2023-2024 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Series IV. Records of Meryem Karad, 2017-2019, Extent: 3.5 boxes (Box 8-11)
  The records of Meryem Karad contain materials covering the following topics and groups: mercury and toxic air standards, climate change, coal ash, conservation, Chesapeake Bay, Clam and Oyster Aquaculture Work Group, the Atlantic Coast Pipeline, Mountain Valley Pipeline, and the DuPont settlement. Meryem was also involved with the Virginia Asian Advisory Board (VAAB). Papers pertaining to VAAB are agendas, minutes, reports, heritage month, Community Leader of the Year, and the Asian American Pacific Islander Summit. Subject files include legislative action summaries, executive orders, correspondence, project documentation, and reports.
  - Executive Order (EO) 2019: Establishment of the Virginia Council on Environmental Justice and related documents, 2018-2019 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Advisory Council on Environmental Justice, 2018 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Appropriations, 2018 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Natural Resources Boards, 2018-2019 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Freedom of Information Act requests and documents, 2018 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Asian Advisory Board (VAAB) internship applications, circa 2017 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Asian Advisory Board (VAAB) commissions of appointment to the Board, 2014-2016 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Virginia Asian Advisory Board (VAAB) Governor Terence R. McAuliffe's Asian American Pacific Islander Summit, 2017 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Asian Advisory Board (VAAB), VAAB Guide for Governor's Office liaison, 2017 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Virginia Asian Advisory Board (VAAB), 1882 Project presentation and pamphlet, 2017 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Asian Advisory Board (VAAB), applicant resumes, circa 2017 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Asian Advisory Board (VAAB), email discussion regarding Asian-Pacific-American Heritage Month, (APAHM), 2018 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Asian Advisory Board (VAAB), Asian Community Leader of the Year applications, 2018 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Asian Advisory Board (VAAB), meeting agendas and minutes, 2017-2018 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Asian Advisory Board (VAAB), annual reports, 2014-2016 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Latino Advisory Board (VLAB), documents, 2018 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Request for extension of Mercury and Air Toxic Standards (MATS) compliance date, 2014 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Request for extension of Mercury and Air Toxic Standards (MATS) compliance date, 2014 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Mandate: Virginia Pollution Abatement permit, 2017 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - PJM correspondence to the Honorable James Richard Perry, Secretary of the Energy, U.S. Department of Energy, 2017 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Candidates for gubernatorial appointment for Governor-Elect Northam, 2017 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Legislative action summaries, 2019 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Climate and Security Advisory Group, Briefer: The U.S. Department of Defense's Forthcoming Climate Change Vulnerability Report, 2018 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Report of Effects of a Changing Climate to the Department of Defense, 2019 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Chesapeake Bay Environmental Literacy Leadership Summit, 2019 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Chesapeake Bay Executive Council correspondence, 2019 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - ConserveVirginia, 2019 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Satchidananda Ashram, Yogaville, Atlantic Coast Pipeline Environmental Justice Impacts, 2018 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Flood Awareness Week, 2019 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Clam and Oyster Aquaculture Work Group Report, 2018 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Virginia Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ), 2018 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Testimony of Matthew J. Strickler: Legislative Hearing on a Discussion Draft Bill, Endangered Species Act Amendments of 2018, 2018 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Outline for equity in all policies with a focus on social determinants of health and well-being, OSHHR team, circa 2018-2019 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Office of the Governor, Executive Orders and correspondence, 2014-2018 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Governor McAuliffe's Climate Change and Resiliency Update, Commission: Report and Final Recommendations to the Governor, 2015 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Coal Ash, circa 2018 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Chesapeake Bay Stakeholders Advisory Group, Secretary of Natural Resources, agenda, 2018 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Virginia Land Conservation Conversation, 2018 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Department of Conservation and Recreation, 2018 (Box 10, Folder 2)